[
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shylock the Meek",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A pitiful beggar",
            "job": "I sit and beg oh... please...",
            "heal": "I am cold and sick! oh... please...",
            "keyword1": "BEG ",
            "keyword2": "SICK",
            "answer1": "Yes, please give me money! oh... please...",
            "answer2": "I have the black plague!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou help me? Oh... please...",
            "yesanswer": "Oh... please...",
            "noanswer": "Oh... please..."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Nigel, at thy service.",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A noble wizard",
            "job": "I teach magical spells.",
            "heal": "Good enough.",
            "keyword1": "SPEL",
            "keyword2": "RECA",
            "answer1": "I have a specialty!",
            "answer2": "Yes, resurrection it takes: ash, ginseng, garlic, silk, bloodmoss, and mandrake!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know what it is?",
            "yesanswer": "What do I call the spell?",
            "noanswer": "Sorry."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 23,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Catriona",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A strong guard.",
            "job": "To watch the treasures.",
            "heal": "Very good.",
            "keyword1": "TREA",
            "keyword2": "VALU",
            "answer1": "The treasures are of great value!",
            "answer2": "Yes, much gold.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou intend to steal?",
            "yesanswer": "I shan't stop thee",
            "noanswer": "Good, you had me worried!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 86,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 12,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Zajac",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A flighty jester",
            "job": "To entertain!",
            "heal": "Unhappy.",
            "keyword1": "ENTE",
            "keyword2": "UNHA",
            "answer1": "Ah, not now.",
            "answer2": "Because my friend Chuckles won't tell me his secret!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know chuckles?",
            "yesanswer": "Why dost thou not ask him for his clue!",
            "noanswer": "He lives in the castle Britannia ask him of his clue!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 26,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 56,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a fighter",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An injured warrior.",
            "job": "None now!",
            "heal": "My wounds are grievous!",
            "keyword1": "WARR",
            "keyword2": "WOUN",
            "answer1": "No more!",
            "answer2": "I lost in a dungeon altar room!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou seen one?",
            "yesanswer": "Notice that each of the three rooms connect to four dungeons each!",
            "noanswer": "They connect the dungeons unto each other!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 56,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a fighter",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An injured warrior.",
            "job": "None now!",
            "heal": "My wounds are grievous!",
            "keyword1": "WARR",
            "keyword2": "WOUN",
            "answer1": "No more!",
            "answer2": "I lost in a dungeon altar room!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou seen one?",
            "yesanswer": "Notice that each of the three rooms connect to four dungeons each!",
            "noanswer": "They connect the dungeons unto each other!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 56,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a fighter",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An injured warrior.",
            "job": "None now!",
            "heal": "My wounds are grievous!",
            "keyword1": "WARR",
            "keyword2": "WOUN",
            "answer1": "No more!",
            "answer2": "I lost in a dungeon altar room!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou seen one?",
            "yesanswer": "Notice that each of the three rooms connect to four dungeons each!",
            "noanswer": "They connect the dungeons unto each other!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 45,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a truth seeker.",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A person lost in thought.",
            "job": "I seek to know truth.",
            "heal": "I am in a meditative state.",
            "keyword1": "TRUT",
            "keyword2": "MEDI",
            "answer1": "The principle upon which I meditate.",
            "answer2": "Meditate at each shrine for 1, 2 and 3 minutes, then shalt thou know the paths of goodness!",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 43,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a truth seeker.",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A person lost in thought.",
            "job": "I seek to know truth.",
            "heal": "I am in a meditative state.",
            "keyword1": "TRUT",
            "keyword2": "MEDI",
            "answer1": "The principle upon which I meditate.",
            "answer2": "Meditate at each shrine for 1, 2 and 3 minutes, then shalt thou know the paths of goodness!",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 39,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a truth seeker.",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A person lost in thought.",
            "job": "I seek to know truth.",
            "heal": "I am in a meditative state.",
            "keyword1": "TRUT",
            "keyword2": "MEDI",
            "answer1": "The principle upon which I meditate.",
            "answer2": "Meditate at each shrine for 1, 2 and 3 minutes, then shalt thou know the paths of goodness!",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a truth seeker.",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A person lost in thought.",
            "job": "I seek to know truth.",
            "heal": "I am in a meditative state.",
            "keyword1": "TRUT",
            "keyword2": "MEDI",
            "answer1": "The principle upon which I meditate.",
            "answer2": "Meditate at each shrine for 1, 2 and 3 minutes, then shalt thou know the paths of goodness!",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 23,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Tymus",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A stately wizard",
            "job": "To welcome thee!",
            "heal": "Very well, thanks!",
            "keyword1": "WELC",
            "keyword2": "FOUR",
            "answer1": "Yes, welcome to the Lycaeum, the keep of truth!",
            "answer2": "The dungeon altar rooms need 4 stones each!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye how many cities follow the principles of truth?",
            "yesanswer": "How many?",
            "noanswer": "Travel and learn!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Estro",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A short druid",
            "job": "Research",
            "heal": "Why I am fine, you too I hope.",
            "keyword1": "REAS",
            "keyword2": "JUST",
            "answer1": "I am looking for the book of justice!",
            "answer2": "It must be here somewhere!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou never committed *any* crime!?",
            "yesanswer": "I believe thou art boasting a lie!",
            "noanswer": "Then speak to the judge in Yew!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 14,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Lord Terence",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall agile man",
            "job": "I am the librarian.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "LIBR",
            "keyword2": "TRUT",
            "answer1": "Herein is the largest store of knowledge in Britannia except the codex!",
            "answer2": "Look under 't'",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou looking for a particular book?",
            "yesanswer": "Which book?",
            "noanswer": "Feel free to browse."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 25,
        "y_pos1": 11,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 33,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 11,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Scatu",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall mage wearing strange armour.",
            "job": "I advise.",
            "heal": "Well!",
            "keyword1": "ADVI",
            "keyword2": "ARMO",
            "answer1": "Thou would be well advised to visit the Seer often!",
            "answer2": "I wear mystic armour.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou a partial avatar?",
            "yesanswer": "When thou art 8 parts avatar, seek Zircon in Minoc and ask of mystics!",
            "noanswer": "Alas."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Jon",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A brawny guard.",
            "job": "I guard the throne room.",
            "heal": "Bit tired.",
            "keyword1": "THRO",
            "keyword2": "TRUT",
            "answer1": "Throne of truth!",
            "answer2": "There are four townes that follow the principle of truth.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know which?",
            "yesanswer": "Good!",
            "noanswer": "There are eight possible combinations of the three principles, there are eight cities!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Jon",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A brawny guard.",
            "job": "I guard the throne room.",
            "heal": "Bit tired.",
            "keyword1": "THRO",
            "keyword2": "TRUT",
            "answer1": "Throne of truth!",
            "answer2": "There are four townes that follow the principle of truth.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know which?",
            "yesanswer": "Good!",
            "noanswer": "There are eight possible combinations of the three principles, there are eight cities!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 38,
        "x_pos1": 10,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Father Antos",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "An old druid, who looks strangely familiar.",
            "job": "I hold great knowledge.",
            "heal": "Old and frail, I've seen many quests!",
            "keyword1": "KNOW",
            "keyword2": "BOOK",
            "answer1": "What is it you seek?",
            "answer2": "Seek ye the book of truth where other books lie.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou on the quest?",
            "yesanswer": "May thou succeed!",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 32,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Palamar",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise old sage",
            "job": "I am an old wizard, but have much to show!",
            "heal": "My bones ache but my mind is sharp!",
            "keyword1": "SHOW",
            "keyword2": "TELE",
            "answer1": "Here in my telescope!",
            "answer2": "Search there by the end, thou shalt find a knob.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou see where?",
            "yesanswer": "Set the dial and thou shalt see!",
            "noanswer": "Look!!!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 20,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A sleepy guard",
            "job": "Guard the gate, guard the baron, guard the baroness, watch the towers....",
            "heal": "Very sleepy.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "HOUR",
            "answer1": "I have been here for hours!",
            "answer2": "Yes, many hours!",
            "yesnoquestion": "See why I'm tired?",
            "yesanswer": "It's hard work and long hours in the baronial guard!",
            "noanswer": "Bum!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 28,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 20,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A sleepy guard",
            "job": "Guard the gate, guard the baron, guard the baroness, watch the towers....",
            "heal": "Very sleepy.",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "HOUR",
            "answer1": "I have been here for hours!",
            "answer2": "Yes, many hours!",
            "yesnoquestion": "See why I'm tired?",
            "yesanswer": "It's hard work and long hours in the baronial guard!",
            "noanswer": "Bum!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 31,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Beth Frasier",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A charming lady",
            "job": "I rule with my Lord.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "RULE",
            "keyword2": "PROV",
            "answer1": "This province.",
            "answer2": "Our people believe in truth as a way of life and live it to the fullest!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou seek truth?",
            "yesanswer": "Then may thou find it!",
            "noanswer": "Then thou shalt not find it!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 31,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Robert Frasier",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A stately baron",
            "job": "I rule this province.",
            "heal": "Very well.",
            "keyword1": "PROV",
            "keyword2": "WORD",
            "answer1": "My Lady Beth can tell thee more!",
            "answer2": "I know but one of three syllables.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou wish to know it now?",
            "yesanswer": "It is 'ver'! Seek ye now the other parts!",
            "noanswer": "Perhaps another time."
        }
    }
]